（一九六九年三月三日）
（美国海军为战机师 成立了一间精英学校）
（目的是教导机师 快将失传的空战技巧）
（以确保在此毕业的 一小撮机师）
（成为世上最一流的战机师）
（他们成功了）
（现在 海军称之为战斗学校）
（战机师则称之为 顶级机师部）
壮志凌云
（印度洋，现代）
- 史葛，早 - 温斯，早
-Morning, Scott  -Morning, Vince
- 威斯，早 - 长官，早
-Morning, Wells  -Morning, sir
你好吗？
Okey
骑鬼者，这儿是空袭部
Ghost Rider, this is Strike
发现不明战机，回程的军官
We have unknown aircraft Inbound, Mustang
循090方飞向敌机
Your vector, 0-9-0 for bogey
上面的是谁？
Who's up there?
美洲狮、灰背隼 马华力和野鹅
Cougar and Merlin and Maverick and Goose
好极，是马华力和野鹅
Great Maverick and Goose
野鹅，快回答
Talk to me, Goose
收到，我看到他了
Roger, I got him.Contact, 20 left at 30 miles
在左面三十哩 以时速九百海海里飞近
Nine hundred knots closure
美洲狮，你听到吗？
Cougar, you hear that?
收到
Roger
- 灰背隼，看到他吗？ - 收到，雷达探测到了
-Merlin, you got him?  -Roger, I've got radar contact
我要亲眼确定他 美洲狮，你去引他上钓
I'll get a visual ID.Cougar, you hook him
收到，我会将他煎皮拆骨
Roger, and I'll clean him and fry him
军官，这是骑鬼者 我们在203方
Mustang, Mustang, this is Ghost Rider, 2-0-3,
他受制于我了 他向270方前进
I've got him inbound, bogey heading 2-7-0,
距离十哩，以九百海海里前进
We're at ten miles, 900 knots closure,
骑鬼者，向上十度 向左三度、零
Ghost Rider, take Angels ten left, 3-0
- 我们今天应该有访客吗？ - 不
Are we supposed to have visitors today? Negative, sir
灰背隼，看看他是不是一个人
-Merlin, see if he's a single
收到
-Roger
野鹅，看到跟踪者吗？
Goose, you see a trailer?
没有，灰背隼
Negative, Merlin
似乎只有他一个
Looks like he's a single
美洲狮，我要和他正面交锋
Cougar, I'm gonna go head-to-head with him
马华力，别乱来，我不同意
Take it easy, Maverick I don't like this shit
我飞高一些 确定是不是只有他一个
I'm gonna break high and right,see if he's really alone
马华力，他以一千海海里接近
We've got 1000 knots closure, Mav
他向着我们飞过来
He's coming right at us
老友，你在想什么？
Okay, buddy, what's on your mind?
天啊，他们有两个人
Holy shit, there's two of them
是米格28 没人试过这么近看到
MiG-28s No one's been this close before
他们究竟在做什么？ 什么位置？
What the hell are they doing here?What's the position?
距离二百五十哩
Two hundred and fifty miles out, sir
二百五十哩，叫他们马上离开
Two hundred and fifty miles? Get them out
美洲狮，你看到米格机一号 我去追二号
Cougar, you've got MiG one.I'm going after MiG two
我在阳光下不见了他
I lost him in the sun
该死，他在做什么？ 灰背隼，你制住他了吗？
Shit What's he doing? You got him, Merlin?
他在四处飞，他跟着我们飞
He's coming around.He's coming around on our tail
该死，被他制住了
Goddamn it This bogey's all over me
- 现在距离多远？ - 二百哩
-What's their range now?  -Two hundred miles, sir
短过一百五十哩的话 就出动五号戒备机
If they break 150 miles, launch the Alert Five aircraft
是，长官
Yes, sir
空速三百，马华力，消灭他
Air speed, 300 Go get him, Mav
我准备锁定导弹
I'm going for missile lock
看看能不能把他吓走
Let's see if we can scare this guy out of here
快锁定，亲爱的
Come on, lock up, baby.Lock up, baby Lock up
锁定吧，已经锁定了
I got him locked Bingo
吓倒他了，马华力 他夹着尾巴逃走
We got him, Mav He's bugging out and going home
军官，我是马华力 米格机二号回去了
Mustang, this is Maverick MiG two is headed home
好吧，他们是什么位置？
All right What's their position?
距离一百八十哩，方位是010
A hundred and eighty miles at bearing 0-1-0, sir
他的导弹瞄准我们了 快点避开他
Cougar, he's got missile lock on us.Get away from this guy
这是怎么一回事？他追着我
What the hell is this shit? He's engaging me
该死，军官 这是骑鬼者117号
Goddamn it, Mustang.This is Ghost Rider, 1-1-7
我被敌机制住了 他用导弹锁定我了
This bogey's all over me He's got missile lock on me
我能得到开火的批准吗？
Permission to fire?
未受袭前不能开火
Do not fire until fired upon
野鹅，他们就在我们下面
Goose, there they are, right below us
米格机在最佳的开火位置 他在美洲狮后面
The MiG's in perfect firing position.He's right on Cougar's tail
不可能，野鹅
No way, Goose.
他早就应该开火了 他只是想激怒我们
He'd have fired by now He's just trying to piss us off
马华力，快来帮我脱身
Maverick, get down here and get this asshole off me
美洲狮，别紧张
Easy, Cougar
带他回来，协助我进入战场
Bring it back, hard right Help me engage
我来了
I'm on my way
我无法射击这个王八蛋
I can't shoot this son of a bitch
看看我们能不能跟他玩玩
Let's see if we can have a little fun with him
你说的“玩玩”就是这样？
Is this your idea of fun, Mav?
你好
Greetings
小心战机
Watch the birdie
天啊，笑死我了
Jeez, I crack myself up
这种景象很精彩 我应该当摄影师
This is a great shot, Mav I should be a photographer
美洲狮
Cougar
你脱身了，米格机一号离开了
your tail is clear MiG one's bugged out
美洲狮，我是马华力
Cougar, this is Maverick
今天玩得真开心呢，是吗？
We've had enough fun for one day, don't you think?
燃料不多了，我们回去吧
I'm getting a little low on fuel, so we're heading home
在甲板上见
We'll see you on deck
飞洲狮，燃料不多，要走了
Cougar, we're running low on gas,we gotta get out of here
美洲狮
Cougar
快没燃料了，美洲狮，快回去
We're on vapor, Cougar Let's do it
美洲狮，快回去
Cougar Come on, Cougar
快飞回舰上，飞洲狮
Let's take it back to the ship, man, Come on, Cougar,
叫他尽快降落，他快没燃料了
Get him on deck as soon as possible.He's gotta be low on fuel
美洲狮，我们要降落
Cougar, we gotta land this thing
我们快没燃料了，你明白吗？
We are way low on gas You understand me?
你没事吧？
You all right, man?
马华力，还有四分三哩 降落时作出通知
Maverick, you're at three-quarters of a mile, call the ball,
收到，马华力快要降落
Roger Maverick has the ball
美洲狮，要降落了，快点回去
Cougar, it is time to land, Let's do it,
野鹅，美洲狮出了事
Goose, Cougar's in trouble
别乱来，我们快没燃料了 快点降落
Come on, Mav, we're getting low on gas.Let's land this sucker
美洲狮
Cougar
该死，马华力
Goddamn it, Maverick
你在做什么？ 我们不够燃料这样做
What are you doing, Mav?we've got no fuel for this
我们要去帮美洲狮
We're going after Cougar
叫他马上降落，这是命令
You tell him to land that plane That's an order
骑鬼者，你接到降落指示
Ghost Rider, you are instructed to land,
马上降落
Land immediately,
你们看到附近有航空母舰吗？
Any of you boys seen an aircraft carrier around here?
我们有点小问题 那架米格机吓坏他了
Mav, we got a little problem up here.That MiG really screwed him up
他大概无法把战机开回去
I don't think he can make it back
美洲狮，不要紧，跟着我飞
You're okay, Cougar Just stay on my wing,
我会带你回去，跟着我
I'll take you all the way in Just stay with me
别紧张，好像逛公园一样
Easy, Cougar Just a walk in the park, buddy
你飞得低了点 低了一点
You're a little low.You're a little low, Coug
老友，快点上升
Come on, buddy, pull up
美洲狮，急速上升
Pull up, Cougar
对了
That's it
快到了
Almost there
比下滑道低了点 还有四分三哩，表示降落
You're a little below glide path, three-quarters of a mile, Call the ball,
收到，降落
Roger, ball,
留心你的高度
We're too low, Cougar.
美洲狮，太低了
We're too low, Cougar
加大动力
Increase power Some more power!
请进
Come in
长官
Sir
美洲狮，你应该在医护室的 你在想什么？
Cougar, you should be in sickbay.What's on your mind?
我的妻儿
My wife and kid, sir
他今天几乎变成孤儿 我从没见过他
I almost orphaned him today, and I've never even seen him
我不知道发生了什么事 但是我很害怕
I don't know what happened up there, but I was so scared
别这样 我们以前也见过这种事
-Come on, we've seen this before
不，长官
-No, sir
压力太大了
I'm holding on too tight
我已经受够了，对不起，长官
I've lost the edge I'm sorry, sir I'm sorry
美洲狮
Cougar
谢谢，马华力
Thanks, Maverick
马华力、野鹅，进来
Maverick, Goose, come in here
- 发生了什么事？ - 我不知道
-What the hell's going on?  -I don't know
Shit
马华力，你刚才做的事很勇敢
Maverick, you just did an incredibly brave thing
可是你应该做的是降落
What you should have done was land your plane
战机是纳税人的，不是你的
You don't own that plane, the taxpayers do
你真是狂妄自大
Son, your ego is writing checks your body can't cash
你试过被开除 失去当小组队长的资格三次
You've been busted.You lost your qualifications as section leader three times
我两次帮你恢复职位
Put in hack twice by me
你却试过高速 飞过控制塔和上将之女
With a history of high-speed passes over five air-control towers and one admiral's daughter
班萍妮？
Penny Benjamin?
- 你这笨蛋能在这儿真是走运 - 谢谢
-And you, asshole You're lucky to be here  -Thank you, sir
别再说废话，马华力 你的家人不是空军中最好的
Let's not bullshit, Maverick,your family name ain't the best in the Navy
你应该比他做得更好 你究竟在想什么？
You need to be doing it better and cleaner than the other guy. Now, what is it with you?
我只想为国效力 当最好的海军战机师
Just wanna serve my country,be the best fighter pilot in Navy, sir
马华力，别骗我了
Don't screw around with me, Maverick
你全凭直觉当机师 而且很出色
You're a hell of an instinctive pilot Maybe too good
我很想开除你 不过我有另一个麻烦
I'd like to bust your butt, but I can't.I got another problem here
我要从队中派人去米拉马
I gotta send somebody from this squadron to Miramar
我要做一些事 我难以置信的事
I gotta do something here.I still can't believe it
我要让你梦想成真 派你去面对一流的海军
I gotta give you your dream shot.I'm gonna send you up against the best
你们两个会进顶级机师部
You two characters are going to Top Gun
你们会和世上的顶级机师 交手五星期
For five weeks,you're gonna fly against the best fighter pilots in the world
你是第二，美洲狮是第一
You were number two, Cougar was number one
美洲狮放弃开战机
Cougar lost it, turned in his wings
你们就成了第一
You guys are number one
记着一件事 你们闯过这么多祸
But you remember one thing: You screw up just this much,
迟早会被调往运送狗屎的
you'll be flying a cargo plane full of rubber dog shit out of Hong Kong
是，长官
Yes, sir
没事了
That is all
改天把米格机的事告诉我
You can tell me about the MiG some other time
两位
Gentlemen
祝你们好运
-Good luck, gentlemen  -Thank you, sir
谢谢
Thank you
（美国空军基地 加州米拉马）
海军在韩战的杀敌比率 是十二比一
During Korea, the Navy kill ratio was 12-to-1
我们一架战机 就能击落敌人十二架
We shot down 12 of their jets for every one of ours
到了越战时比率降至三比一
During Vietnam, that ratio fell to 3-to-1
我们的机师太依赖导弹了
Our pilots become dependent upon missiles
他们失去了一些空战技巧
They had lost some of their dogfighting skills
成立顶级机师部 是为了教导你们空战策略
Top Gun was created to teach ACM: Air Combat Maneuvering
也就是空中格斗
Dogfighting
真令人兴奋
This gives me a hard-on
到了越战末期 比率回升至十二比一
By the end of Vietnam, that ratio was back up to 12-to-1
别跟我开玩笑
-Don't tease me
请下窗帘
-Blinds, please
我想藉着这次机会 介绍指挥官给大家认识
I'd like to take this opportunity to introduce you to our commanding officer at Top Gun
他是第一位获得 顶级机师奖的人
The very first man to win the Top Gun trophy
你不会在其他地方找到 比他更优秀的机师了
You will not find a finer fighter pilot anywhere in the world
麦米克长官，外号毒蛇
Commander Mike Metcalf Callsign: Viper
各位
Gentlemen
你们是海军空战人员中 最好的百分之一
You are the top one percent of all naval aviators
是精英，精英中之精英
The elite The best of the best
我们会令你们更进一步
We'll make you better
你们每天至少 要执行两项空中任务
You'll fly at least two combat missions a day,
当中要上课 听取自己表现所得到的评价
attend classes in between and evaluations of your performance
你们在每次的空中任务 都要面对新挑战
On each combat sequence, you're gonna meet a different challenge
每一次都会更加困难
Every encounter is gonna be much more difficult
我们会教你们 令F14尽展所长
We're gonna teach you to fly the F-14 right to the edge of the envelope,
你们会比以前开得更快
faster than you've ever flown before
也会更加危险
and more dangerous
各位，我们不是在这儿立法
Now, we don't make policy here, gentlemen
立法是由获选的官员 和平民做的
Elected officials, civilians do that
我们只是这些政策的工具
We are the instruments of that policy
虽然我们不是在打仗 但要假装是
And although we're not at war,we must always act as though we are at war
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我只是在想谁是最一流的机师
-The tip of the spear best be sharp  -I'm just wondering who's the best
你们可能会想 谁是最一流的机师
In case some of you wonder who the best is,
他们的名字就在墙上的板子上
they're up here on this plaque on the wall
最佳机师和他的通讯员的名字 都会记录在上面
The best driver and his RIO from each class has his name on it
他们可以选择回来当教官
And they have the option to come back here to be Top Gun instructors
你认为你的名字会在上面？
You think your name's gonna be on that plaque?
是，长官
Yes, sir
你真自大，周围有这么多人
That's pretty arrogant, considering the company you're in
是，长官
Yes, sir
我喜欢机师自大
I like that in a pilot
记着，离开这儿后 我们都是同一队人
Just remember, when it's over out there,we're all on the same team
各位，这儿是教大家战斗的
Gentlemen, this school is about combat
当第二是没意思的
There are no points for second place
解散
Dismissed
做得好
Nice going
后补者的徽章在女洗手间
The plaque for the alternates is down in the ladies' room
天啊，真是笑死我了
Oh, Jesus Oh, you kill me You really do
不，“野鹅” 是两个O的
No, no, no There's two O's in "Goose", boys
真是一个不愁没目标的环境
This is what I call a target-rich environment
你在两腿之间生活
You live your life between your legs, Mav
野鹅，连你也可以来这儿
Goose, even you could get laid in a place like this
能找到说脏话的女孩 我就高兴了
I'm telling you, I'd be happy to find a girl who'd talk dirty to me
马华力 你想知道谁是一流机师？
Mav, you wanted to know who the best is?
就是他，冰佬
That's him Iceman
因为他开战机时十分冷静 从不犯错
That's the way he flies, ice-cold, no mistakes
磨灭你的耐性、令你沮丧 你一犯错就会被他逮住
Just wears you down.You get bored, frustrated, do something stupid, and he's got you
滑行者
Hey, hey, Slider
我还以为你想做机师 发生了什么事？
Thought you wanted to be a pilot, man What happened?
野鹅，你真是个蠢才 你是靠谁进来的？
Goose, you're such a dickhead.Whose butt did you kiss to get in here?
名单很长，不过很有名
Well, the list is long but distinguished
我的庄逊也是
Well, so is my johnson
你和冰佬一起飞行？
So you're flying with Iceman, huh?
你应该说冰佬先生
-It's Mr Iceman to you
野鹅妈妈，你好吗？
-Hey, Mother Goose How's it going?
很好，汤姆，这位是麦彼得
Good, Tom This is Pete Mitchell,
卡汤姆
Tom Kazansky
- 恭喜你加入顶级机师部 - 谢谢
-Congratulations on Top Gun  -Thank you
美洲狮的事真令人遗憾
Sorry to hear about Cougar
他和我在飞行学校时情如手足 他以前很好
He and I were like brothers in flight school -He was a good man  -Still is a good man
- 他现在还是 - 我就是这个意思
Yeah, that's what I meant
- 我也以为是 - 需要帮忙吗？
-Thought so  -Say, you need any help?
帮忙什么？
With what?
你想到了吗？
You figured it out yet?
什么？
What's that?
谁是最佳机师
Who's the best pilot
还没有，我自己会想到的
No, I think I can figure that one out on my own
听说你喜欢单独行事
I heard that about you You like to work alone
你一定是在幸运星之下行事
Mav, you must've soloed under a lucky star, huh?
先是米格机 然后又闯进美洲狮的战场
I mean, first the MiG,and then you guys slide into Cougar's spot
我们不是闯进去 那也是我们的战场
We didn't slide into Cougar's spot.It was ours, okay?
有些机师到退役时 还没试过近距离见过米格机
Some pilots wait their whole career just to see a MiG up close
你们一定是既幸运又出名了
Guess you guys are lucky and famous, huh?
你想说的是臭名远播吧
No, you mean notorious
再见
-I'll see you later
一定会
-You can count on it
他们被人宠坏了
They were abused children
- 我们会有一段好时光 - 常常如此
-We're gonna have a good time  -Always
这次应该轮到我吧
Okay, I guess it's my turn, isn't it?
- 打赌二十元 - 好
All right, the bet is $20 -Twenty dollars  -Right
你得对欲海有认识 才能勾搭这时在这儿的女人
You have to have carnal knowledge,of a lady this time, on the premises On the premises
这始终是一场赌博
Come on, Mav A bet's a bet
我不知道 只是这似乎对你不太公平
I don't know, it just--It just doesn't seem fair For you, I mean
她失去了爱的感觉
But she's lost that loving feeling
什么？不，她还没失去
-She's lost--? No, she hasn't
- 她失去了 - 她还没失去...
-Yes, she has -She has not lost that--
- 野鹅，她失去了 - 你少来
-Goose, she's lost it  Mav--Come on
该死，我讨厌她这样做
I hate it when she does that Shit
对不起，小姐
Excuse me, miss
别担心，我会帮你弄妥
Hey, hey, hey.Don't worry, I'll take care of this
（我吻你时你不再闭上双眼）
You never close your eyes anymore When I kiss your lips
（你的指尖不再温柔）
There's no tenderness like before
（你努力掩饰，亲爱的）
You're trying hard not to show it Baby
（可是，相信我，我知道的）
But, baby, believe me, I know it
（你已经失去了爱的感觉）
You've lost that loving feeling.That loving feeling
（你失去了爱的感觉）
You've lost that loving feeling
（感觉一去不返）
Now it's gone, gone, gone
坐下吧
Sit down
谢谢
Thank you
（亲爱的，我会为你下跪）
Baby, baby, I get down on my knees for you
我喜欢这首歌 从没见过这种搭讪
I love that song I've never seen that approach
你们两个试过多少次？
How long have you two been doing this act?
- 我不知道，从... - 青春期开始？
-Oh, I don't know, since  -Puberty?
对
Right, puberty
- 我叫布莎洛 - 我叫马华力
-I'm Charlotte Blackwood  -I'm Maverick
马华力？你妈妈不喜欢你吗？
Maverick? Did your mother not like you or something?
不，这是我的外号
No, it's my callsign
你是战机师
-You're a pilot
是，我是海军空战人员
-That's right, a naval aviator
其实我们这样做只试过两次
No, actually, we've only done this twice
结果怎样？
Oh, how'd you do?
第一次是一场大灾难 不太好看
Crashed and burned on the first one It wasn't pretty
第二次呢？
-The second?
我不知道，明天告诉你 暂时还不错
-I don't know I'll tell you tomorrow But it's looking good so far
马华力
Well, Maverick,
我的朋友刚到了 和你谈得真愉快
my friend's just arrived, so it's been great talking to you
彼利
-Perry  -Hi
你来了，我马上回来
Hi Here you go I'll be with you in just a second, okay?
我可以问你一个私人问题吗？
Listen, can I ask you a personal question?
视乎你问什么
That depends
你是好机师吗？
Are you a good pilot?
我认为我是
I can hold my own
好极 我不用担心你要靠唱歌维生了
Great Then I won't have to worry about you making your living as a singer
我需要啤酒来救火
I'm gonna need a beer to put these flames out Yo!
好极，真狡猾
Great, Mav Real slick
水手，你出了海很久吗？
It was a long cruise, was it, sailor?
太久了
It was too long
你想怎样，就地进行吗？
What did you wanna do,just drop right down on the tile and go for it?
不，其实我是想在这张桌子
No, I actually had--Had this counter in mind
好极，一定会很舒服
Great, that would be very, very comfortable Yeah
可能会
It could be
其实我来是希望你不会 为那个老鬼做错误决定
Actually,I came in here to save you from making a big mistake with that older guy
真的？ 那我就能和你这种年轻人好？
Really?So I could go on to a bigger one with a young guy like yourself?
可能吧
Maybe No?
明天一早我便要工作
I've gotta be at work very early in the morning
你在这儿做什么？
Then what are you doing here?
你的朋友真厉害
Your friend was magnificent
No
你们也会受到 平民专家的训练和评估
Now, you'll also be trained and evaluated by a few civilian specialists
这儿有平民 是因为他们对敌机很有认识
The civilians are here because they are our very best source of information on enemy aircraft
其中最有资格的 就是教官代表，外号狐狸
One of the most qualified is our TAGREP,callsign: Charlie
她是天体物理学哲学博士
She has a PhD in astrophysics,
她也是一个平民承包商 你们不用向她敬礼
and she's also a civilian contractor,so you do not salute her
不过最好听她的 因为军方相信她对你们的评估
But you better listen to her,because the Pentagon listens to her about your proficiency
- 交给你了，狐狸 - 谢谢
-It's all yours, Charlie  -Thank you
大家好
Hello
我们会用F5和 A4模拟米格机
We will be dealing with F-5s and A-4s as our MiG simulators
你们大多都应该知道
Now, then, as most of you know,
F5不像米格28 可以打破重量比率
the F-5 doesn't have the thrust-to-weight ratio the MiG-28 has
更不会像米格28 在少于三百海海里时漏出能量
And it doesn't bleed energy below 300 knots, like the MiG-28
不过米格28的反飞行油箱 的确有问题
However, the MiG-28 does have a problem with its inverted flight tanks
它不能做负引力飞行动作
It won't do a negative-G pushover
最新的情报告诉我们
The latest intelligence tells us that the most it will do
它最多能够做负一...
is one negative--
对不起，上尉
Excuse me, lieutenant
有什么问题吗？
Is there something wrong?
是，米格机的资料不正确
Yes, ma'am, the data on the MiG is inaccurate
哪儿不正确？
How's that, lieutenant?
- 我看过米格28... - 是我们
-Well, I just happened to see a MiG-28 do-- -We, we
对不起，野鹅
Sorry, Goose
我们见过米格28 做四个负引力俯冲
We happened to see a MiG-28 do a four-G negative dive
你在哪儿见到？
Where did you see this?
这是机密资料
-That's classified
什么？
-It's what?
是机密资料
It's classified
我可以告诉你 但是之后就要杀了你
I could tell you, but I'd have to kill you
上尉，我有权知道最高机密
Lieutenant, I have top-secret clearance
军方要我比你知道得更多
The Pentagon sees to it that I know more than you
那么这次大概不同了
Well, ma'am, it doesn't seem so in this case, now, does it?
上尉，你当时在哪儿？
So, lieutenant where exactly were you?
- 我们... - 谢谢
-Well, we  -Thank you
我们从他后面开始 他穿越云层，我飞到他上面
started up on his 6 when he pulled through the clouds,and then I moved in above him
你在他上面又怎会看到他？
Well, if you were directly above him, how could you see him?
因为我倒转了
-Because I was inverted
废话
-Bullshit
不，他真是这样做
No, he was, man It was a really great move
好精彩呢，他倒转了
He was inverted
你和米格28一起 做四个负引力反转俯冲？
You were in a four-G inverted dive with a MiG-28?
是
Yes, ma'am
- 距离多远？ - 大概两米吧
-At what range?  -About two meters
实际上是一米半
It was actually about one and a half, I think
我拍下了当时的精彩景象
It was one and a half.I've got a great Polaroid of it
他没错，一定是一米半
He's right there It must be one and a half
- 是张好照片 - 谢谢
-It was a nice picture
上尉
-Lieutenant
你当时在做什么？
What were you doing there?
沟通
-Communicating  -Communicating
是沟通，保持外交关系
Keeping up foreign relations
我当时在向他喝倒彩
I was You know, giving him the bird
用手指表示
-You know, the finger
我明白，野鹅
-Yes, I know the finger, Goose
对不起，我讨厌它这样
I'm sorry, I hate it when it does that I'm sorry
对不起
Excuse me
原来是你
So you're the one
是
Yes, ma'am
好吧，各位，我们要飞行了
All right, gentlemen, we have a hop to take
假设地面在一万英尺 无论如何不能低过这高度
The hard deck on this hop will be 10000 feet.There'll be no engagement below that
出发
Move it
上尉
Lieutenant
别再迟到，亲爱的
Okay, well, don't be late again.You look great, honey
谢谢，在预飞区见
Thanks, dear See you in preflight
上尉，你为什么不告诉我 是你羞辱米格机
Lieutenant,why didn't you tell me that you were the famous MiG insulter?
我说了会有分别吗？
Would it have made any difference?
在女洗手间里不会
Not in the ladies' room, no
那我们呢？
What would've?
我是这儿的教官
I'm an instructor at this school
每八个星期就会见到 二十个雄心勃勃的新丁
I see 20 new hotshots every eight weeks
你一定能想像得到
Now, I'm sure you can figure that out
上尉
Look, lieutenant
我真的很想听听米格机的事
I'd just really like to hear about the MiG sometime
你有权看最高机密 你可以自己看
You've got security clearance.You can read about it
马华力
Maverick
我很好奇
I'm curious
你戏弄米格机时 是谁在掩护美洲狮？
Who was covering Cougar while you were showboating with this MiG?
美洲狮表现很好
Cougar was doing just fine
Gentlemen, this is your first hop,
你们面对的战机更小、 更快 也更容易控制
The jets you are flying against are smaller, faster and more maneuverable,
就像米格机一样
just like the enemy MiGs,
计时开始，我们要保持优势
The clock is ticking and as of now,we are keeping score,
我不见了他，野鹅
I lost him, Goose
小子，让我看看你有什么能耐
Show me what you got, kid
不见了他
-I lost him
我在找他了
-I'm looking, I'm looking
看到了，他在我们后面冲过来
I got him, I got him.He's on our tail, coming hard
我看到他了，行动
I got him I got him Here we go
好吧，把资料告诉我，野鹅
All right, talk to me, Goose
他仍然在很后面，急速飞过来
He's still back there He's closing in on us.He's closing fast
小子，你可以逃，但是躲不掉
You can run, kid, but you can't hide
笑匠，看看我能不能逼你尽力
Come on, Jester.Let's see if I can give you a run for your money here
小心撞山
Watch the mountains
我仍然看到他，他仍然在后面
I still got him He's still back there
马华力，快点想办法
Come on, Mav Do some of that pilot shit
我看到他了
Yeah, I got him
快点锁定
Come on, bring it right
野鹅，我受够了
Goose, I've had about enough of this shit
我要踏制动器，他就会飞过头
I'm gonna hit the brakes, he'll fly right by
你们死定了
Okay, you're mine
天啊
Jesus Christ
看看你现在的境况，笑匠
Let's see what you've got now, Jester
扭转局势吧
Okay, Mav, let's turn and burn
他垂直飞，我也是
He's going vertical, so am I
我们好像在弹射一样
We're going ballistic, Mav Go get him
他要飞向假设地面 快比他抢先一步
He's going for the hard deck.Let's get down there first and nail him, Mav
不行，笑匠，你死定了
No way, Jester, you're mine
我瞄准你了
I got you now
笑匠输了
Jester's dead
马上飞高回基地
Get your butts above the hard deck and return to base immediately
遵命
Yes, sir
控制塔，骑鬼者要求低飞
Tower, this is Ghost Rider requesting a flyby
骑鬼者，不行，航线繁忙
Negative, Ghost Rider, the pattern is full
不，马华力，这不是个好主意
No No, Mav This is not a good idea
对不起，野鹅 是时候飞过控制塔了
Sorry, Goose, but it's time to buzz the tower
臭小子
Goddamn son of a bitch
真是精彩绝伦
Great balls of fire!
笑匠输了
Jester's dead
你们赢了，废话
-You won? That's bullshit
不是大家都赢了吗？
-Didn't everybody?
是才怪，我们都惨败而回
Hell, no, man, we got our butts kicked
在三十秒内我们这样，他这样
Thirty seconds We went like this, he went like that
我问好莱坞他在哪儿 他竟然问我谁在哪儿？
I said to Hollywood, "Where'd he go?"Hollywood said, "Where'd who go?"
他就在对讲机上取笑我们
Yeah, and he's laughing at us,right on the radio He's laughing at us
不，笑你们的是我，笨蛋
No, it's me laughing, dickhead
我们赢了
-We won
好
-All right
他们也赢了呢
They won too, man
- 我没听说过 - 是真的，我们打败了笑匠
-That's not what I heard  -No, we did, we got Jester
不，低过假设地面不算
No, no Below the hard deck does not count
假设地面？总之我们打败了他
Hard deck, my ass.We nailed that son of a bitch
你们真爱自吹自擂
-You guys really are cowboys
卡汤姆，你有问题吗？
-What's your problem, Kazansky?
你是大家的问题
You're everyone's problem
因为你每次飞行都不安全
That's because every time you go up in the air,you're unsafe
我不喜欢你，因为你很危险
I don't like you because you're dangerous
对，冰佬
That's right, Iceman
我很危险
I am dangerous
马华力
Maverick, you and Goose get your butts out of that flight gear
你和野鹅马上脱掉飞行衣 到毒蛇的办公室
and up to Viper's office now
记着，当第二名是没分的
Remember, boys, no points for second place
- 你们比看来更聪明 - 住口
-You're a lot brighter than you look  -You shut up, okay?
- 别担心，野鹅 - 我会
-Don't worry, Goose, don't worry  -Okay, I will
有这两个自大狂 以四百多海海里飞过控制塔
Two of your snot-nosed jockeys did a flyby on my tower at over 400 knots!
我要你们找人负责，我受够了
I want somebody's butt I want it now I've had it
该死，第二次了
Goddamn it! That's twice
一定要有人负责
I want some butts!
正好解释了飞过控制塔的事
Well, that'll just about cover the flybys
跟我来
Follow me
两位，你们第一天过得真充实
Gentlemen You had a hell of a first day
这次任务的假设地面是一万英尺
The hard deck for this hop was 10000 feet
你们明知故犯
You knew it, you broke it
希军官不见了你们之后 你们跟着他低飞
You followed Commander Heatherly below after he lost sight of you and called no joy
为什么？
Why?
长官，我看到希军官
Sir I had Commander Heatherly in my sights.He saw me move in for the kill
他看到我飞到开火的位置 就飞低过假设地面
He then proceeded below the hard deck
我们只有几秒低飞了
We weren't below 10000 for more than a few seconds
我瞄准了他 见没有危险就开火
I had the shot, there was no danger, so I took it
你开了火，你破坏了重要守则
You took it And broke a major rule of engagement
飞越控制塔时又犯了另一条
Then you broke another one with that circus-stunt flyby
麦上尉
Lieutenant Mitchell, Top Gun rules of engagement exist
守则是为了你 和队员的安全而设立的
for your safety and for that of your team
守则不可随时更改，我也是
They are not flexible, nor am I
不遵守的话就要被开除 清楚了吗？
Either obey them or you're history.Is that clear?
是，长官
Yes, sir
解散
Dismissed
我真的很享受那一下，谢谢你
I really enjoyed that, Mav, thanks a lot
天啊
Holy shit
我或者可以学习当货车司机
Maybe I could learn how to be a truck driver
你有货车驾驶学校的电话号码
Mav, you have the number of that truck-driving school we saw on TV?Truck Master, I think it is
我可能会需要到
I might need that
评估报告已经显示了他很飘忽
His fitness report says it all.He's a wild card
他靠直觉开战机 完全无法预测
Flies by the seat of his pants.Completely unpredictable
- 他吓倒你了？ - 是
-He got you, didn't he?  -Yeah
马华力，我曾经和他爸爸共事
Maverick I flew with his old man
告诉我 你想和他一起上战场吗？
Tell me one thing.If you had to go into battle, would you want him with you?
我不知道
I don't know
我真的不知道
I just don't know
还没睡吗？
-You still awake?
是
-Yeah
你在想什么？
What's up?
睡不着
Can't sleep
我知道可以进顶级机师部时 我只想拿机师奖
You know, when I first realized that we were going to Top Gun, all I could think about was getting that trophy
我要坦白跟你说
I gotta be straight with you, Mav
我现在只希望我们能毕业
Right now, I just hope we graduate
我有家人 我不能浪费这个机会
I got a family to think about.I can't afford to blow this
其实飞越控制塔不算什么
Yeah, I guess that flyby wasn't such a big hit
我知道你很难受
Look, man, I know it's tough for you
他们因为你是麦杜克的儿子 而不让你进海军学院
They wouldn't let you in the academy because you're Duke Mitchell's kid
你要承受这个污名
You have to live with that reputation
我们每次飞行时 你都像在面对鬼魂一样
But it's like every time we go up there,it's like you're flying against a ghost
你令我紧张
It makes me nervous
我只有你这个亲人
You're the only family I've got
我不会令你失望的，我保证
I'm not gonna let you down I promise you
出去吧
Get out of here
在这情形下 倒转打转会很有效
A rolling reversal would work well in that situation
如果我十字形倒转飞 就能马上转为发炮
If I reversed on a hard cross,I could immediately go to guns on them
在这种速度下，太快了
Yeah, but at that speed, it's too fast
而且太过急进
It's a little bit too aggressive
太过急进？
Too aggressive
我觉得应该这样做就这样做
Yeah, I guess when I see something,I go right after it
你没告诉我你那晚去了哪儿
You didn't tell me who you were the other night
你没有给我机会说
You didn't give me a chance, did you?
你应有此报
You deserved it
我知道 不过有人想你约我吃晚餐
I know But you were tempted to ask me out for dinner
不
-No  -No?
- 不？ - 我不和学员约会
No I don't date students
我看得出这对你很危险
I can see it's dangerous for you
但是如果政府相信我 你也可以
But if the government trusts me, maybe you could
这不只是花式飞行这么简单
It takes a lot more than just fancy flying
（今晚五点半共进晚餐）
一败涂地，马华力？
Crash and burn, huh, Mav?
滑行者
Slider
你很臭
you stink
开始
Let's go
冰佬，快打
Okay, Ice, hit it
That's good Come on
Let's go, now
Come on, Mav, 4-7 Let's get them.Those guys are animals
Let's go
Good serve, good serve
That's game
Okay Fake block, stay down.We'll just take them
Come on, where you guys going?You walking away?
We won, we won
马华力，再打一局 就追成平手了
Mav Mav Come on, man.Just one more game That evens it up
我们很大机会会赢的 我们有实力
-Come on, we can take them  -No
我要去办一件事
-No, we can, we got it  -I got some things I gotta take care of
办事？只是再打一局而已
Take care of? Just one more game
- 为了我好吗？ - 对不起
-Please? For me?  -I'm sorry
你应该内疚，来吧
You're sorry Come on -Mother Goose, you pussy!  -For me?
该死
Damn it
上尉
Lieutenant?
不唱歌了吗？
What, no singing?
- 我... - 不用道歉
-Look, I'm--I'm-- -No apologies
你不介意的话 我想去快快洗一个澡
If you don't mind, I'm--I'm gonna just take a quick shower
让你好好吃完
while you're finishing up here
可是我介意，我很饿
Yeah, I do mind I'm hungry
后来我想起来了
And then I thought about it
我想
I thought:
狐狸，他是个聪明人
You know, Charlie, he's a smart guy
为什么不干脆告诉他 请他来的目的？
Why don't you just tell him why you've got him here"
是什么？
Well?
米格机
It's the MiG
是米格机 只有你曾经面对过米格28
The MiG You're the only pilot who's been up against a MiG-28
我正在努力工作 希望能够升职
I'm trying for this big promotion at work, and if I get it,
成功的话，我不会再留在这儿
I'm not gonna be here much longer
你似乎什么都想清楚了
It seems to me you've got it all figured out
是
Yeah
只是你忘记了酒
Except you did forget the wine
对不起
Sorry
你常常如愿以偿？
You always get what you want?
不...可能是吧
No, not always Yeah, maybe
那就别这么在意那架米格机
Then relax about the MiG
这首音乐...
This music
是老朋友的？
An old friend?
我父母很喜欢这首音乐
My folks loved it
我有很多年没听过了
I haven't heard this in years
妈妈以前在房里 叫我把它不停重播
My mother used to call down from her room and have me play this over and over again
我很厌倦听这首音乐
I got so sick of it
她却没有
But not her, she
她会独坐在一旁 一听就听上几个小时
Just sit up there alone, just listening, hours
她会跟着唱
Just listening
他死后不久她也死了
She died shortly after him
你爸爸怎样死的？
What happened to your father?
你既然有权知道机密资料
I guess I kind of figured, with your security clearance,
应该比我知道得更多
you'd know more about him than I do
我还没知道得这么深入
Well, I didn't get that far
这是一个谜
Well, it's a big mystery
他在1965年11月5日 开着F4失踪
He disappeared in an F-4, November 5th, 1965
听说是他犯错了，不可能
The stink of it was, he screwed up No way
我爸爸是很优秀的机师
My old man was a great fighter pilot
但谁知道呢？ 一切都被列作机密资料
But who the hell knows?It's all classified
一定有人知道的
Somebody must know
有人什么都知道
Yeah, somebody knows everything
所以你总是只能拿到第二名？
Is that why you're always second best up there?
你真直接呢
You are direct, aren't you?
对不起，我迟到
I'm sorry I was late
对不起，我这么直接
I'm sorry for being direct
不用道歉
No apologies
这会变得很复杂
This is gonna be complicated
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
我去洗澡
I'm gonna take a shower
谢谢，我玩得很高兴
Thank you I enjoyed being here
你似乎需要再洗一个澡呢
It looks like you need another shower
对
Right
我想对你坦白
I'm gonna be honest with you
你看到米格机 会对我的工作大有帮助
Your MiG sighting is really important to my work, but
但我不是常常请学员 到家中作客的
I don't normally invite students to my house
你是...
You're
希望你明白我有工作在身
But please understand, I still have a job to do
长官，你好
-Morning  -Sir
我很高兴我们这么坦白
I'm glad we got that straight
我告诉她这儿有多辛苦
I told her how tough it is here
我累得跟死狗一样
You know, my ass dragging like an old, tired dog
我告诉她你在这儿 连一个女人也没有
I told her that you didn't even have a woman here
够了
-Oh, really  -You know what she said?
知道她怎样说吗？ 他可能有八个呢
Said, "Well, he probably doesn't have one, he's got eight"
爸爸
Daddy
马华力
So, Maverick,
野鹅说你和教官坠入爱河了
Goose tells me you're in love with one of your instructors
- 是吗？ - 我没说过这件事
-Is that right?  -I--I didn't tell her that
你有说过的
Yes, you did
你竟然说出来，那是秘密
-Yes, you did  -I can't believe you said that -That was a secret  -No
敌机在很好的位置，请定格
The bogey has good position right here.All right, freeze-frame
是抉择的时刻了
Moment of choice
F14是防守性的 它有机会逃回基地
The F-14 is defensive He has a chance to bug out right here
最好先撤退和保存战机安全
Better to retire and save your aircraft
接着进入了更差的位置
than push a bad position
狐狸，你可以随时插嘴
Charlie, jump in here anytime
你在菱形内再多留三秒
Now, you stay in that diamond another three seconds,
就会被敌机消灭
the bogey's gonna blow you out of the sky
如果你选择第五区向右突围
You take a hard right, select zone five,
就能拖延时间逃走
you can extend an escape
你作了一个很差的决定
You made a bad choice
狐狸
Charlie
战机一号翻了一个分裂S筋斗
Aircraft one performs a split S?
这是你最不该做的 米格机就在你后面
That's the last thing you should do.The MiG's right on your tail
请定格
Freeze there, please
你在米格机的射程范围 你现在会想什么？
The MiG has you in his gunsight  What were you thinking at this point?
你没时间在空中思想了
You don't have time to think up there
一想就死定了
If you think, you're dead
用价值三千万元的战机打赌 赌得可真大呢
Well, that's a big gamble with a $30 million plane, lieutenant
不幸地，他赌赢了
Unfortunately, the gamble worked
米格机无法开火
The MiG never got a clean shot
马华力做了 富侵略性的垂直飞行
Maverick makes an aggressive vertical move here,
到了顶部 他用导弹打败了敌机
comes over the top,and he defeats the bandit with a missile shot
这次的交手是一次胜利
The encounter was a victory,
不过这是不该做的例子
but I think that we've shown it as an example of what not to do
下一个
Next
从没见过这么大胆的行动
Gutsiest move I ever saw, man
接着的可以作为 教科书的最佳例子
Now, then, this is a perfect example of a textbook maneuver
上尉
Lieutenant
Maverick
上尉...
Lieutenant Lieutenant
我对你的飞行评估 是我的专业意见
My review of your flight performance in the TACTS was right on, in my professional opinion
我听不到你说什么
I can't hear you
天啊，你以为我只会鲁莽行事
Jesus Christ! And you think I'm reckless
我飞行时就会让你知道 我以队员和战机为先
When I fly,I'll have you know that my crew and my plane come first!
上尉，让我把话说完
Well, I'm going to finish my sentence, lieutenant
我对你的飞行评估是正确的
My review of your flight performance was right on
- 是吗？ - 是的
-Is that right?  -That is right
但是我保留了一些
But I held something back
我看得出你有飞行的天才 但是我不能在那儿说出来
I see some real genius in your flying,Maverick, but I can't say that in there
我害怕大家会看穿我
I was afraid that everyone in that TACTS trailer would see right through me
我只是不想让人知道 我爱上你了
And I just don't want anyone to know that I've fallen for you
马华力，听到冰佬的事吗？
-Hey, Maverick  -Yeah You hear about Ice?
- 什么事？ - 他又赢了
-What's that?  -He won another one
真的？
-Really?  -Yeah
我感觉到我需要速度
I feel the need, -the need for speed  -The need for speed
各位，这是第十九次飞行
Gentlemen, this is hop 19,
会有更多战机和敌机
Multiple aircraft, multiple bogies,
训练已经过了一半 最佳机师奖的争持仍然激烈
Your training is half over,The competition for the Top Gun trophy remains tight,
第一名是冰佬
First place, Iceman,
第二名是马华力，只差两分
Second place, Maverick, just two points behind,
他们来了
There they are
在三哩外，西北方 大概还没见到我们
Three miles, left, 10 o'clock.I don't think they see us yet
我看到他们
Okay, I see them
左边有两架A4，在西北方 继续左转
Two A-4s, left 10 o'clock level, continue left turn
各位早安，气温是110度
Good morning, gentlemen.The temperature's 110 degrees
天啊，是毒蛇
Holy shit, it's Viper
毒蛇在空中，好极
Viper's up here, great
该死
Oh, shit
他可能也在说该死 是马华力和野鹅
Great He's probably saying,"Holy shit, it's Maverick and Goose"
他一定在这样说
Yeah, I'm sure he's saying that
我看到北方的敌机
I've got my eye on the northern bogey
收到，我看到南方的
Roger I got the southern guy
好莱坞，你先行，我掩护你
Hollywood, you've got the lead, I'll cover you
笑匠，快转弯
Break now, Jester
好莱坞，我们失去了毒蛇 对付笑匠吧
Hollywood, we're losing Viper.Let's just stay on Jester
收到，我去对付他
Roger, I'm on him
野鹅，找毒蛇出来 他一定在什么地方
Goose, find Viper He's out there somewhere
和好莱坞一起，我们要掩护他
Stay with Hollywood, Mav, we're covering his wing
野鹅，是毒蛇，他在东方
Goose, there's Viper 3 o'clock, low
和好莱坞一起，我们在掩护他
Stay with Hollywood, Mav We're his cover
马华力，别离开我
Don't you leave me, Maverick
好莱坞，你进展良好
Hollywood, you're looking good
我去对付毒蛇
I'm going after Viper
马华力，去你的
Goddamn you, Maverick
马华力，别离开他
Mav, don't leave him
野鹅，好莱坞没事的 我想打败毒蛇
Goose, Hollywood's okay I want Viper
毒蛇会被打败
Stand by Viper's coming down
该死，我们面对面了 我们竟然这样做
Holy shit, we're head-to-head.I can't believe we're doing this
摇滚一下吧
Rocking roll
机不可失，野鹅
Here's our chance.It's a big one, Goose
加油，该死
Come on, goddamn it
马华力，加油
Come on, Mav, keep coming
选定响尾蛇导弹
Okay Sidewinder missile selected
快锁定
Come on, baby Come on, baby
来吧，对了
Come around, come around.That's it, that's it
天啊，他真厉害
Jesus, this guy's good
野鹅，他去了哪儿？
Goose, where's he going?
继续
Come on, come on, come on, keep coming Keep coming
加油
Come on, baby
该死，这小子真厉害
Damn, this kid's good
他太接近，不能用导弹 改为用枪炮
He's too close for missiles,Goose, I'm switching to guns
快
Come on, come on, come on
Stick with me, stick with me
等一下，野鹅，看看后面
What--? Hold it Goose, check our tail
是笑匠
Shit There's Jester
成功了，马华力输了 小子，你玩完了
Bingo, Maverick's dead.You're out of there, kid
该死
Shit
防卫部很遗憾要告诉你
The Defense Department regrets to inform you
你的儿子因为太笨而战死沙场
that your sons are dead because they were stupid
真刺激
Great balls of fire
算了吧，大家回去 由毒蛇带头
Okay, knock it off, gentlemen.Let's go home Viper has the lead
还有三十秒，我和人狼就进来
Thirty seconds, Wolfman, and I'm coming in
-Shut up!  -God, buttnose
我从没见过这么精彩的空战
That was some of the best flying I've seen yet,
直至你们被打败为止
right up the part where you got killed
你永不该离开同伴
You never, never leave your wingman
马华力
Maverick
问题不在你的飞行技术 而是你的态度
it's not your flying, it's your attitude
敌人很危险
The enemy's dangerous,
但是你比敌人更加危险
but right now you're worse than the enemy
你既危险又愚蠢
You're dangerous and foolish
你未必喜欢你的战友
You may not like the guys flying with you,
他们也未必喜欢你 你究竟是帮哪一方？
they may not like you, but whose side are you on?
起码毒蛇在打败我们之前 打败了冰佬
Well, at least Viper got Iceman before he got us
我们仍然有机会得奖
We still got a shot at it
那是愚蠢的行为，我也知道
That was stupid I know better than that
不会再发生这种事
It'll never happen again
我知道
I know
我知道的
马华力，制止他吧 他没试过令你难为情吗？
Maverick, would you go fetch him?Doesn't he ever embarrass you?
野鹅，当然没试过
Goose? Hell, no Well, there was the time
- 有一次... - 上将的女儿
-Admiral's daughter  -What?!
什么？
Come on
他把你和班萍妮的事告诉我了
He told me all about the time you went ballistic with Penny Benjamin
是吗？好极
Did he? Well, that's great
他把一切都告诉我了
He tells me about all of them, Maverick
我的小天使野鹅 早早回家准备去教堂
How my little angel Goose goes home early for church,
你就常常带火辣辣的女人回家
and you, you always go home with the hot women
好吧，谢谢你，嘉露
All right, thank you, Carole
我去和野鹅一起难为情一下
I'm gonna go embarrass myself with Goose for a while
我想警告你，马华力很危险
I would love to be able to warn you off about Maverick,
可是我很喜欢他
but I just love him to death
我认识了彼得很多年
You know, I've known Pete for a lot of years now,
有一件事我可以肯定的告诉你
and I'm telling you, one thing's for certain
今晚世界上会有很多人心碎
There are hearts breaking wide open all over the world tonight
为什么？
-Why?
因为...除非你是个笨蛋
-Because unless you are a fool,
他已经不再在情场上鬼混了
that boy is off the market
他是百分百、 史无前例地 爱上了你
He is 100 percent, prime-time in love with you
野鹅，臭男人
Hey, Goose, you big stud!
我的确是，亲爱的
That's me, honey
和我上床 否则你会永远失去我
-Take me to bed or lose me forever
教我怎样回家，亲爱的
-Show me the way home, honey
乖儿子，和家人一起唱
Come on, brother, sing with the family
马华力，臭男人
Maverick you big stud,
和我上床 否则你会永远失去我
take me to bed or lose me forever
各位，这是第三十一次飞行
Okay, gentlemen, this is hop 31,
你们还有两星期就毕业了
Two weeks to graduation,
最佳机师奖的得主仍然未落实 每一分都很重要
Top Gun trophy is still up for grabs,  so every point counts,
争持这么激烈 是时候来一次大获全胜了
Well, it's bottom of the ninth, the score is tied.It's time for the big one
马华力，你这次能赢吗？
You up for this one, Maverick?
这跟在公园散步一样容易
Just a walk in the park, Kazansky
请联络，有多架敌机 一、 六、 五...
Contact Multiple bogies, 1-6-5
距离两哩 他们似乎想远离我们
Two miles Looks like they're going away from us
我看到了，就在东北方 我来了
Ho, I see them, tallyho, right 2 o'clock I'm in
我也加入
I'm in
这个臭小子截住我了
That son of a bitch cut me off
快，天啊
Come on, come on Jesus Christ.
冰佬，快开火
Ice, take the shot
冰佬，快点走开
Come on, Ice, get the hell out of there
角度还没确定 太近了，不能用导弹
I can't get the angle.I'm too close for missiles
现在改为用枪炮
I'm switching to guns
冰佬，你不开火就走开
Ice, fire or clear
天啊，我在这儿也能开火
Look at this! Jesus Christ,I can take a shot right here!
我只需要多二十秒
I need another 20 seconds, then I've got it
我来了，我已经锁定了
I'm moving in I've got the shot
马华力，上
Come on, Mav, let's get in there!
快
Come on, Mav!
马华力不耐烦了 冰佬，快开火
Maverick's getting impatient.Come on, take the shot
再多十秒就行了
Ten more seconds, then I've got him
冰佬，快走开
Come on, Ice, get the hell out of there!
马华力，出手吧
Let's do it, Mav
冰佬，从右边走开，我要上来
Ice, come off high right I'm in
再多五秒
-Five more seconds
去右边，冰佬，我来了
-Come off high right, Ice I'm in
我走开，该死
I'm off Shit!
我们在喷气流之中
-We're in his jet wash!
该死
-Holy shit!
该死，引擎停了，马华力
This is not good Shit, we got a flameout, Mav
引擎一号停了
Engine one is out
引擎二号也停了
Engine two is out!
野鹅，我无法控制战机
Goose, I'm losing control I'm losing control
失去了控制，无法回复正常
I can't control it It won't recover
该死
Shit
祸不单行
It's coupling up, Mav! We're out of control
情况不妙
This is not good! This is not good!
请求救援，马华力出事了 机身在不停打转
Mayday, mayday Mav's in trouble.He's in a flat spin
快掉进海里了
He's heading out to sea
高度八千，现在是六千
Altitude 8000, 7000
Six We're at six, Mav
我被抛到前面，野鹅
I'm pinned forward, Goose.
我摸不到跳机杆
I can't reach the ejection handle
野鹅，你要帮我们弹出去
Goose, you're gonna have to punch us out
我摸不到跳机杆
I can't reach the ejection handle Eject
- 快点 - 我在尽快了
-I'm trying! I'm trying!  -Eject! Eject!
- 快 - 小心机舱盖
Eject! Watch the canopy!
野鹅，不
Goose! Goose! Oh, no!
天啊
Oh, God! Oh, God! Oh, God
请你放手，你一定要放手
Sir, let go of him You gotta let him go, sir
你怎样？
How you doing?
我没事
I'm all right
野鹅死了
Goose is dead
我知道
I know
开战机开得久了 总会遇到这种事
You fly jets long enough,something like this happens
他是我的通讯员 这是我的责任
He was my RIO, my responsibility
我在越战的部队 十八架战机有八架坠毁
In my squadron in Vietnam,we lost eight of 18
总共十条人命
aircraft Ten men
第一个人死了，你也会死
First one dies, you die too
你可以肯定还会有其他人
But there will be others You can count on it
放过自己
You gotta let him go
放过他
这可能是我的错
I think maybe it was my fault
我不知道是哪儿出错
I don't know what the hell went wrong
我想帮你，我知道你很难接受
I'd like to help I know it's difficult
天啊，我想他复活
God, I want him back
你需要我的话随时找我
I'll be here if you need me, okay?
天啊，他很喜欢和你并肩作战
God, he loved flying with you, Maverick
就算没遇上你，他也会当机师
But he'd have flown anyway without you
虽然他会讨厌这种事 但他还是会做
He'd have hated it, but he would've done it
我们发现这架F14的引擎 卷进了气流
We find that the F-14 flat spin was induced by the disruption of airflow into the starboard engine
这种干扰令引擎 出现过多的偏航率
This disruption stalled the engine,which produced enough yaw rate
结果令机身不停打转 无法修正
to induce a spin which was unrecoverable
这种问题 不是麦上尉可察觉到的
There was no way Lieutenant Mitchell could either see or avoid the jet wash which produced the engine stall
所以资询会发现
Therefore, the board of inquiry finds that Lieutenant Pete Mitchell
麦彼得上尉 并没在7月29日的意外犯错
was not at fault in the accident of 29 July
这次的意外 不会记在麦上尉的纪录上
Lieutenant Mitchell's record will be cleared of this incident
麦上尉马上复职
Lieutenant Mitchell is restored to flight status without further delay
调查完毕
These proceedings are closed
尽快让他回复飞行
Get him up flying, soon
小子，快点进战场
Come on, kid, come on Get in there Engage
马华力，东北方有一架敌机
All right, you got a bogey at 2 o'clock low, Maverick
你的位置很好 简直是轻而易举
You got the angle Piece of cake, pal
快开火，小子
Take the shot, kid Take the shot
马华力，你随时都可以加入
You can engage any time, Maverick
你要去哪儿？
Hey, where the hell are you going?
情况不妙
It's not good It doesn't look good
情况不妙是什么意思？ 情况好到不得了
What do you mean, it doesn't look good?It doesn't get to look any better than that
你本来可以击中他的 我们可以击中他的
Hey, man, we could've had him.Hey, we could've had him, man!
我准备好时自然会发炮
I will fire when I am goddamn good and ready!
你明白了吗？
You got that?!
他仍然未回复过来 他不愿战斗
He can't get back in the saddle Won't engage
只过了几天
It's only been a few days
他可能不能回复过来
You know, he just might not make it back
Keep sending him up
麦彼得
Mitchell
我很难过野鹅死了
I'm sorry about Goose
大家都喜欢他
Everybody liked him
我很难过
I'm sorry
你好，我是人狼
Hi, it's Wolfman
马华力刚刚退学了
Yeah, Maverick just quit
对不起
Excuse me
我可以坐下吗？
May I?
随便
Please
和他要的一样
I'll have what he's having
是毒药吧
Hemlock, is it?
是冰水
Ice water
你不和我道别吗？
You weren't gonna say goodbye?
听说你得到华盛顿的工作了
I heard you got that job in Washington
恭喜
Congratulations
谢谢
Thanks
但是我不会不辞而别
But I wasn't gonna leave without saying goodbye
看到你真好
It's good to see you
谢谢
Thanks
你要去哪儿？
Where you going?
你连机票也没有吧
You don't even have a ticket, do you?
我看过所有证据 这不是你的责任
Listen, I've seen all the evidence,and it's not your responsibility
不是你的错 你是海军里的精英
It's not your fault You're one of the best pilots in the Navy
你在高空战斗是很危险
What you do up there, it's dangerous
但是你得继续下去
But you've got to go on
你不明白
You don't understand
我刚认识你时 你的生活很充实
When I first met you, you were larger than life
看看你
Look at you
你不过步伐急速的生活 你不会快乐
You're not gonna be happy unless you're going Mach 2 with your hair on fire,
你知道的
-you know that  -No, it's over
不，完了 做精英中的精英
-It's just over  -To be the best of the best
就是犯错后仍然继续努力
means you make mistakes and then you go on.
这对大家来说都一样
It's just like the rest of us
你以为我不知道吗？
You don't think I know that?
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help
谢谢你
Look, thank you
我想别人帮我的话 自然会开口
But if I wanted help, really,I would have asked for it
原来我来迟了
So I'm too late
你已经离开了
You've already left
你什么都没学到
You didn't learn a damn thing, did you?
你只学会退缩
Except to quit
你真的很擅长做这种事呢
You've got that maneuver down real well
再见了，麦彼得
So long, Pete Mitchell
你好，马华力，请进
Well, hi, Maverick, come on in
- 你好吗？ - 我很好
-How are you doing?  -Good
- 真的，你真的没事？ - 我很好
-Really? You sure you're feeling okay?  -Oh, I feel great
- 珍美，你要喝点什么吗？ - 不必了
Jamie, come on.Can I get you a drink or anything else like that?
请随便坐，米克马上就下来了
-No, thank you  -Okay, well, why don't you just make yourself comfortable Mike will be right down
谢谢
Great, thank you
你爸爸和我在奥利士卡尼号的 VF51小队并肩作战
I flew with your old man VF-51, the Oriskany
你真的很像他
You're a lot like he was Only better and worse
他是一个天生的英雄主义者
He was a natural heroic son of a bitch, that one
他真的没做错
So he did do it right
是的，他没做错
Yeah, he did it right
所以你这样开战机？ 你想证明什么？
Is that why you fly the way you do?Trying to prove something?
你爸爸的确没做错
Yeah, your old man did it right
我要告诉你的事是机密事件 可能会令我丢掉工作
What I'm about to tell you is classified.It could end my career
我们置身于一场 我梦寐以求的战斗之中
We were in the worst dogfight I ever dreamed of
敌机像萤火虫般布满天空
Bogies like fireflies all over the sky
他的F4战机被击中，他受了伤
His F-4 was hit, he was wounded,but he could've made it back
他本来可以回基地 但是他留在战场
He stayed in it, saved three planes
在坠毁之前救了三架战机
before he bought it
我怎么会从没听说过？
How come I never heard that before?
州政府不会告诉家属
That's not something the State Department tells dependents
因为地图出错而发生战事
when the battle occurred over the wrong line on some map
- 你当时在场？ - 是
-So you were there?  -I was there
你在想什么？
What's on your mind?
我的选择
My options, sir
很简单
Simple
你已经拿到足够分数 出席明天的毕业礼
First, you've acquired enough points to show up tomorrow and graduate with your Top Gun class
否则就退学
Or you can quit
这不是丢脸的事 那样打转我也会被吓倒
There'd be no disgrace That spin was hell.It would've shook me up
你认为我应该退学？
So you think I should quit?
我没说过
I didn't say that
你觉得是你害了野鹅 而且有信心危机
The simple fact is, you feel responsible for Goose,
我不会坐在这儿跟你说好话
Now, I'm not gonna sit here and blow sunshine up your ass, lieutenant
一个好机师必须评估发生的事
A good pilot is compelled to always evaluate what's happened
这样才能学以致用
So he can apply what he's learned
到了高空我们就要全力以赴 这是我们的职责
Up there, we gotta push it That's our job
上尉，这全看你的选择
It's your option, lieutenant, all yours
对不起，在周日打扰你
Sorry to bother you on a Sunday, sir,
谢谢你抽空见我
but thank you very much for your time
不要紧，祝你好运
No problem Good luck
（房子出租）
各位
-Gentlemen
马华力在哪儿？
-Where's Maverick?
我不知道他在哪儿
I don't know where he is
你知道他有什么打算吗？
You know what he's planning to do?
他一定是很难过
Gotta be hard on the guy, though
恭喜
Congratulations
谢谢
Thank you
- 恭喜 - 谢谢
-Congratulations  -Thanks, Mav
长官
Sir
各位
Gentlemen
我讨厌要在派对 失去控制前把它结束
I hate to break up the party before it really gets out of hand,
但是我们有事要做
but there is work to be done
你们有一些人要马上离开
Some of you have to depart immediately
我们遇上了危机
We have a crisis situation
- 冰佬、 滑行者 - 有
-Ice, Slider  -Yo
- 好莱坞、 人狼 - 是
-Hollywood, Wolfman  -Yes, sir
- 马华力 - 是
-Maverick  -Sir
马华力 你到达母舰就会有通讯员
Maverick, you'll get your RIO when you get to the ship
找不到的话
And if you don't
通知我，我和你一起飞
give me a call I'll fly with you
是
Sir
（24小时后，印度洋）
各位，这是靶心
Gentlemen, this is bull's-eye
通讯船SS赖顿号失去功能 闯进了外国区域
The communication ship SS Layton has become disabled and has wandered into foreign territory
一小时内会开始营救行动
A rescue operation is to begin within the hour
你们的任务 就是空中支援营救行动
Your mission is to give air support to that rescue
该区有米格机，十分紧张
There are MiGs in the area, and tensions are high
受到袭击可以还火
If you witness a hostile act, you will return fire
米格机有很厉害的导弹
Those MiGs carry the Exocet anti-ship missile
他们可在一百哩以外发射导弹
They can fire that missile from 100 miles away
各位，这是真正的战斗
Gentlemen, this is the real thing.
这是你们的受训目的
This is what you've been trained for
你们是美国的精英 令我们感到光荣吧
You are America's best Make us proud
- 冰佬 - 是
-Ice  -Yes, sir
- 好莱坞 - 是
-Hollywood  -Yes, sir
第二组
Sector two
马华力，你和灰背隼做后援
And Maverick,you back them up with Merlin on Ready Five
是
Yes, sir
起立
Rise!
- 对不起 - 什么事？
-Excuse me, sir  -Yes
我不针对人 但是对马华力来说
This is not personal, but with regard to Maverick,
他是最好的...
is he the best backup--?
我知道你在想什么 总之你照着办吧
I know what's on your mind,Kazansky, just get on it
军官，有机会时替我检查一下
Mustang, can you give me a mode-four check?
伏都一号，有两架敌机在北方 距离十五哩
Voodoo one, you've got a pair of bogies,12 o'clock, 15 miles
伏都一号，090
Voodoo one, Voodoo one, 0-9-0,
雷达显示在十五哩
radar contact 15 miles
他们的时速是五百海海里
They're doing 500 knots
收到，那就是你的敌机
Roger, that's your bogey
他们在正前方十五哩 速度六百海海里
Got them dead ahead, 15 miles,air speed is 600 knots
Bogies' air speed, 650, We're a little close together,Let's take a wider split,
现在在一万五千英尺 正前方十哩
They're at 15000 feet now,dead ahead, ten miles,
正在加速
Air speed is still increasing,
八百海海里，正前方八哩
Eight hundred knots Dead ahead, now, eight miles.Dead ahead, now, eight miles
好莱坞，看到他们吗？
-Wood, you got them?
还没看到，看不到
-Not yet, I can't see them
一定是接近，我很兴奋
They must be close, I'm getting a hard-on
好莱坞，我先走一步 确定他们的位置
Okay, Wood, I'm taking the lead.Let's identify them
收到，冰佬 你先走，我在你左下方
Roger, Ice, you got the lead.I'm on your left side, a little low
马华力已经准备好出动
Maverick's up and ready in Alert Five
好极
Good, good
好莱坞，仍然被锁定 他在你左边
Hollywood, my bogey's still locked up,He's drifting to the left,
以090的航道飞行
Still maneuvering course 0-9-0,
好莱坞 飞向右边会有较好的角度
Okay, Wood, let's bring it to the right,and we'll get a better angle on them,
冰佬，我们有麻烦
Ice, we got a problem here
我们在雷达上发现了四架战机
Now I'm breaking out four aircraft on the radar
不是两架，是四架敌机
Not one pair, two pair Repeat, four bogies
好莱坞，有四架敌机
Wood, we've got four bogies
弄错了，是五架
-Wrong! Make that five!
- 是五架 - 五架？
-There's five, sir -That's five?
是
-Yes, sir
该死
Oh, shit!
他用雷达锁定了我们
He's got a radar lock on us!
好莱坞，快离开
Get out of there, Hollywood!
快避开，去你的
Get out of there, goddamn it!
转左
-Break left!
被击中了，我们崩溃了 我无法控制战机
-I'm hit! I'm hit! We're coming apart!I can't control it! Hold on!
我们在下降
-We're going down!  -Wood's been hit! Wood's been hit!
好莱坞被击中，该死
Shit! Wood's been hit!
伏都一号，好莱坞被击中 失去好莱坞了
Voodoo one! Wood's been hit!Wood's been hit! We've lost Hollywood!Repeat, we've lost Hollywood!
叫马华力出动
-We've lost our wingman,-Launch Maverick on Alert Five
找出好莱坞和人狼的位置 出动救援直升机
Get a bearing on Hollywood and Wolfman and launch the rescue helicopter immediately,
- 马华力起飞了 - 冰佬，你在哪儿？
-Maverick's airborne  -Iceman, what's your position?
090，180哩以外
0-9-0 at 180 miles
在左边来
We're coming in left!
有两架米格机在正前方 从左飞向下
Three MiGs, dead ahead,coming down the left side
我去对付他们 令他们飞到左边
I'm going after them.I'm bringing it around to the left
我们后面有四架敌机 总共是六架
We got four on our tail!That makes six of them! Who do you think is hooking in the guns range?
他开火了，转右
He's firing! Break right!
这是伏都一号，我们只能防守 快出动戒备战机
Mustang, this is Voodoo one, we are totally defensive
他们在哪儿？
-Launch the alert fighters,  -Where are they?
从160哩以外高速飞来
A hundred and sixty miles and closing in fast, sir
叫韦勒和森坚准备
Ready Willard and Simkin off CATs three and four
马华力以超音速赶来 三十秒内赶到
Maverick's supersonic I'll be there in 30 seconds
马上赶来，我们身陷险境
Move your ass! Get up here!I'm engaged with five Repeat, five I'm in deep shit!
韦勒和森坚怎样？
What about Willard and Simkin?
两部发射器都坏了 不能再发射战机
Both catapults are broken.We can't launch any aircraft yet, sir
- 要多久才能修好 - 十分钟
-How long?  -It'll take ten minutes
十分钟？两分钟内就玩完了 快想办法
Bullshit, ten minutes.This thing will be over in two minutes Get on it!
一架米格机在北方
One MiG, 12 o'clock high!One MiG, 12 o'clock high!
小心后面
Watch your back! Watch your back!
转右
Break right!
该死，很接近，马华力
Shit, that was close! Maverick, how about some help here?
小子，快来
-Where the hell are you?  -Come on, kid, hang in there
天啊
Jesus Christ
马华力，快援手 快进入战场，该死
Maverick, how about some help?Engage, goddamn it!
马华力，后面有一架米格机
Maverick, we got a MiG on our tail
小心
Watch out! Watch out!
该死，我们刚刚飞过喷气流
Shit, we just flew right through his jet wash
快点控制机身
Get control, Mav! Get control!
我们修正好了，现在进战场吧
Good recovery, Mav Okay, let's get in there
我们要帮助冰佬
Come on, we gotta help Ice
快点回战场，马华力
Come on, let's get back in the game, Maverick!
- 快进去 - 我办不到
-Come on!  -No It's no good -Get in there, Maverick!  -It's no good
去你的，马华力竟然退缩
Goddamn it! Maverick's disengaging!
我早就知道会这样，该死
I knew it! Shit!
去你的，马华力
Goddamn it, Maverick!
马华力，你不能离他而去 你在做什么？
Get in there, Maverick!You can't leave him! Come on! Maverick! -What the hell are you doing?  -Talk to me, Goose
野鹅，和我说话
Get in there, for chrissake! -Ice is in trouble!  -Talk to me, Goose Get in there, Maverick!He won't last down there alone!
Get in the fight, for chrissakes!
Maverick! Maverick!
马华力重返战场了
Maverick's reengaging, sir
我无法摆脱他
I can't get him off my tail!
冰佬，你的米格机在我正前方
Ice, I've got your MiG dead ahead.I've got him dead ahead
好目标，锁定
Good tone I've got good tone
发射
I've got tone! I've got tone! Firing!
- 他们在哪儿？ - 155哩外
-Where? Where are they?  -A hundred and fifty-five miles
两架米格机在正前方 时速八百哩
Two MiGs, dead ahead.Closing at 800 miles an hour
我看到了，我要引一架去左边
I see them I see them.I'm gonna take them down the left side
天啊
Oh, my God
冰佬在我们下面 他后面有一架米格机
Ice is right below us.He's got a MiG on his tail
他开火了，左转
He's firing! Break left! Break left!
射过头了
He overshot! He overshot!
冰佬，我来了
Coming in, Ice I'm coming in
前面有两架米格机
I got two MiGs dead ahead
我看到一架 一架飞过我们身边
I got him, Mav One MiG passing between us
有一架米格机在你左边
You got a MiG on your left.On your left! 3 o'clock!
在东方，他要开火了
He's gonna fire, he's gonna fire!
马华力，小心北方的米格机
Maverick, check the guys to the north!Check the guys to the north!
左转
Banking left Banking left
他在那儿
There he is Get him,
冰佬，消灭他
Ice Get him!
好，我来了
Okay, you guys, I'm coming in!
马华力，有一架米格机在后面 我们要离开
Maverick, we got a MiG coming around on our tail!
我不能离冰佬而去
-We gotta get out of here!  -I can't leave Ice
他仍然在前进 他要在我们后面
He's still coming around!He's gonna get behind us!
我不会离同伴而去
I'm not leaving my wingman
我在他后面，我要向他发炮
I'm on his tail I'm on his tail.I'm going for it I'm going for it.I'm going for the shot right now
收到，准备
Roger Engaged
已经锁定了雷达
I've got radar lock
锁定，我要发炮
Good tone I'm taking a shot
发炮
Fire!
- 成功了 - 消灭那个笨蛋了
-Bingo!  -Wash that sucker, yeah!
冰佬，小心 右边有一架米格机
Ice, watch out  There's a MiG to your right
他发炮了
He's firing!
我被击中了
I'm hit! I'm hit!
我们的右引擎被击中
We're hit in the right engine!
我正在把它关掉
I'm shutting it down
冰佬，快逃
Coming in, Ice Coming in
冰佬，敌机仍然在你后面 我预备发炮
Ice, that bogey's still behind you.I'm maneuvering for a shot
别放过他，马华力
Stay with him, Mav, stay with him!
快发炮，击落他
-Take the shot! Nail him! Nail him!
冰佬，我无法锁定目标
-Shit Ice, I can't get a tone
快发炮，马华力 我无法摆脱他
Shoot, Maverick! I can't get him off my tail!
马华力，我们又被击中了
-Maverick, we're hit! We're hit again!  -It's okay
不要紧，引擎仍然能运作 我们没事
Both engines are functioning We're okay
冰佬，我数三声后向右突围
Ice, on the count of three,break hard right!
三、 二、 一，向右突围
Three, two, one Break right!
开火
Firing!
该死，射不中
Damn it, I missed!
别放过他，继续攻击他
Don't let him go.Keep on him, Mav Keep on him
我看到他了
I got him I got him
再来一记
Here comes a shot
Scratch three!
马华力，快避开 后面有米格机
Maverick, move! There's a MiG on your tail!There's a MiG on your tail!
我们有麻烦，只剩下一颗导弹
We've got a problem here.We've only got one missile left
以时速110哩接近
-Approaching 110 miles, sir
该死
-Goddamn it
我看到他了，他就在我们后面
I got him! I got him! He's right on us!He's between our tails!
Shit
还没失去他的踪影 他仍然没有走
You haven't lost him He's still with us!
你在做什么？你竟然减速？
What are you doing?You're slowing down! You're slowing down!
- 我要引他飞近一点 - 什么？
-I'm bringing him in closer, Merlin  -You're gonna do what?
马华力，是时候了
This is it, Maverick!
我要踏制动器，让他飞过头
I'm gonna hit the brakes, he'll fly right by
该死，他会锁定我们
Shit! He's gonna get a lock on us!
就是现在
Now!
锁定了，发炮
I got a good lock Firing
全取四分
Scratch four!
军官，这是伏都三号 余下的米格机都撤离了
Mustang, this is Voodoo three.Remaining MiGs are bugging out
军官，这是马华力，请求飞过
Mustang, this is Maverick requesting flyby
不批准，骑鬼者，航道繁忙
Negative, Ghost Rider The pattern is full
对不起，有该让我知道的事吗
Excuse me Something I should know about?
谢谢
Thank you
臭小子
Goddamn that guy
（马华力一麦彼得）
你
You!
你仍然很危险
You are still dangerous
不过你随时可以做我的战友
You can be my wingman anytime
废话，你也可以做我的战友
Bullshit You can be mine
- 马华力 - 长官
-Maverick  -Sir
成为所有英文报纸的头条 有什么感觉？
How does it feel to be on the front page of every newspaper in the English-speaking world?
虽然另一方否认这件事 恭喜你
Even though the other side denies the incident, -congratulations  -Thank you, sir
谢谢
They gave you your choice of duty, son
他们让你选择你的职务
Anything, anywhere Do you believe that shit?
你想去哪儿？
Where do you think you wanna go?
我想当教官
I thought of being an instructor, sir
- 教顶级机师部？ - 是，长官
-Top Gun?  -Yes, sir
愿主保佑我们
God help us
麦彼得，你好
Hello, Pete Mitchell
听说精英中的精英回来了 所以...
I heard the best of the best were gonna be back here,so
这会变得很复杂
This could be complicated
第一次是一次大灾难
You know, on the first one,I crashed and burned
第二次呢？
And the second?
我不知道
I don't know, but
不过暂时看来还不错
it's looking good so far